How to enable telemetry in Business
Central online environments. To enable
telemetry for a Business Central online
environment,
you go to the tenant admin center and
pick the environment. In this case, I
have an environment called DK Sandbox.
And in the details menu here, I have an
ability to set application insights
connection string. Let me click this
define.
And this opens up a new menu where I can
put in a connection string that will
allow Business Central to start emitting
telemetry to this application insights
resource.
Be aware that this will trigger if if
you save this, it will trigger restart
of the environment. So, please don't do
this during working hours.
But I will just click enable application
insights and then I need to supply a
connection string. How do I get that?
Well, we simply need to go to the Azure
portal to our application insights
resource and get it there. Let's do
that.
So, here in the Azure portal on the
front page of my application insights
resource,
I have a menu called essentials on the
front page and here I have connection
string. So, I simply go to the right and
click copy to clipboard.
And this is the connection string I need
to put into the tenant admin center. So,
let's go back there.
I click connection string field and I
paste my connection string in here. And
when I click save, again important, this
will trigger an environment uh
restart. When I click save, this will
inject the connection string into
Business Central and within a few
minutes, you now start getting data.
That's how
easy it is to enable telemetry on a
Business Central environment.